

## Recent Employment

#### 2010 - 20

## **Head of Engineering**

Meetupcall

Leading a development team and building the technical side of a leading UK conference call provider from the ground up.

Originally a Ruby / Rails monolith, over recent years I successfully migrated key performance sensitive parts of the infrastructure to Elixir to help with scalability concerns.

Duties have included:

#### Leadership

- Recruiting / dismissing employees.
- Managing departmental budget.
- Performing employee reviews.
- Mentoring junior developers.
- Engaging in weekly one-to-ones with team members.

## • Back-end development work

- Using Ruby and Rails to build web applications, RESTful APIs, scripts, daemons, libraries and jobs.
- Using Elixir with Absinthe to build a fast, scalable GraphQL APIs

#### • Front-end development work

- Using Vue.js and GraphQL to create a dashboard that allows a customer to view a visual representation of a conference call in real time. The customer can control the call - see who is speaking and kick or mute attendees.

### · Following industry best practices

- Following a lightweight Agile process stand-ups and sprints, pair programming where appropriate.
- Ensuring our code is well tested, especially business logic and critical code paths and utilising TDD where appropriate.
- Using CI / CD tools to automate our deployment process.
- Embracing 'infrastructure as code' and provisioning our server infrastructure using dev-ops tools including Terraform, Chef and Ansible.

#### Addressing scaling concerns - keeping things fast

- Benchmarking and using tools like NewRelic to identify issues.
- Parallelisation and distribution of tasks using Resque / Sidekiq.
- Heavy use of caching especially Redis.
- Judicious extension of Ruby / Asterisk with C / C++.

## · Addressing reliability concerns - keeping things running

- Implementing tools like Monit, Rollbar and Slack to keep us informed when things go wrong.

## Information

Name John Knott
Nationality British

Work 20 Years Experience
Phone +447510718735
Email john.knott@gmail.com

## About Me

I've been a professional software engineer since I was 17 years old. I started my career as C / C++ developer using Visual Studio 1.5, wrangling with now archaic concepts such as near / far pointers, memory models and inline assembly.

Recent programming work has been primarily Rails, Elixir, Vue.js and Flutter.

I have a keen interest in learning new languages and paradigms - I think it is crucial not to let skills stagnate.

When not working or learning new things I enjoy running, travelling and playing table-tennis.



## Previous Employment

## 2009 -10 Software Developer

Smiffys UK

Building APIs and Data Access Layers. Integrating legacy and contemporary systems. Automating business processes.

Technologies: C#, .NET, SQL Server, Silverlight, Entity Framework, SOAP / REST APIs

## 2007 -09 Software Developer

Miller Bros Retail Ltd

Enhancing and maintaining a complex C++ web application that served pages for a high traffic retail website.

Technologies: C, C++, STL, GDB, Valgrind, Oracle, Postgres, HPUX, SOAP, Ruby / Rails

## 2006 -07 Web Developer

Data, Media and Research Ltd

Developing software, writing scripts, building websites and fixing bugs for a direct marketing and competitions company.

Technologies: HPUX, Oracle, Debian, Ruby / Rails, Perl, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Apache, Vim

## 2004 -06 Founder

**Cubic Studios Ltd** 

Running my own business designing, developing and hosting websites for clients.

Technologies: Linux, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bash

## 1998 -04 Software Developer

**Prozone** 

While at Prozone, I was part of a small team developing football and rugby match analysis solutions used by top club teams for Windows platforms. Clients included Manchester United, Arsenal, Liverpool, Real Madrid and Ajax.

This role involved working in a high pressure real-time environment - software I created was used to capture data for high profile clients such as the BBC and ITV for their The Premiership program.

I worked extensively on the companies flagship product - ProZone - a sports analysis tool which helps study every aspect of a game . I also created an application that captured synchronised video from multiple cameras at football stadiums.

Technologies: Visual C/C++, MFC, C#, .NET, Image processing, Flash, Sockets, SQL, COM, DirectX, Reverse engineering

## Summary of Skills

#### **Recent Technical Skills**

Ruby / Rails	••••
Elixir	••••
VueJS	••••
Flutter	••••
Linux	••••

### **Paradigms**

Procedural	••••1
Object Oriented	••••
Functional	••••

## Education

Hatfield High School - 1992 - 1995

GCSE: Mathematics A, Science Single Award B, Science Double Award B, English Language B, English Literature B, Geography B

**Doncaster College - 1996 - 1997** NVQ Level I, II, and III in Computing

# Examples of recently completed online courses and books I've read

- \* Complete Flutter Dev. Bootcamp with Dart
- \* Machine Learning Andrew Ng
- \* Complete Elixir and Phoenix Bootcamp
- \* Designing Data-Intensive Applications
- \* The Rust Programming Language

## Online

**Github\*** johnknott **Twitter** johndknott

\* The majority of my work is in private repositories.